I'd like to say welcome brothers and
sisters to another Wednesday question
and answer where we open up with the ten
commandments that God commanded for the
whole world to keep. Brother James.
>> Yes sir. And God spake all these words
saying, I am the Lord thy God which had
brought thee out of the land of Egypt
out of the house of bondage. Thou shalt
have nor the gods before me. Thou shalt
not make unto thee any graven image, or
any likeness of anything that is in
heaven above, or that is in the earth
beneath, or that is in the water under
the earth. Thou shalt not bow down
thyself to them, nor serve them. For I,
the Lord thy God, am a jealous God,
visiting the iniquity of the fathers
upon the children unto the third and
fourth generation of them that hate me,
and showing mercy unto thousands of them
that love me, and keep my commandments.
Thou shalt not take the name of the Lord
thy God in vain. For the Lord will not
hold him guiltless that taketh his name
in vain. Remember the Sabbath day to
keep it holy. Sixth day shalt thou labor
and do all thy work, but the seventh day
is the Sabbath of the Lord thy God. In
it thou shalt not do any work, thou nor
thy son, nor thy daughter, thy man's
servant, nor thy maid servant, nor thy
cattle, nor thy stranger that is within
thy gates. For in six days the Lord made
heaven and earth, the sea, and all that
in them is, and rested the seventh day.
Wherefore the Lord blessed the Sabbath
day, and hollowed it. Honor thy father
and thy mother, that thy days may be
long upon the land which the Lord thy
God giveth thee. Thou shalt not kill,
thou shalt not commit adultery. Thou
shalt not steal. Thou shalt not bear
false witness against thy neighbor. Thou
shalt not covet thy neighbor's house.
Thou shalt not covet thy neighbor's
wife, nor is man's servant, nor his
maid's servant, nor his ox, nor his ass,
nor anything that is thy neighbors. I
read Exodus 20:es 1-1 17. May the Lord
add a blessing to the reading of this
word. In Jesus name we pray. Amen.
>> Amen. Right?
>> So here on question and answer, you can
ask us a question and we'll answer it
according to the King James Bible. And
if we cannot find the answer, we will
seek further counsel to bring you an
answer at a later time. The questions we
will not answer are the vague as well as
the long scripture questions and
questions of debate. We are not here to
debate. We are here to spread the true
gospel of Jesus. So, please be as direct
as possible with your questions so we
can be as direct as possible with our
answers out of the King James Bible. No
other Bibles or books will be
acknowledged on this program. Also, keep
in mind that this is a live stream, so
feel free to send in your questions that
pertain to everlasting life. We just
asking that you please keep them to a
two scripture maximum.
And I would also like to say happy day
of atonement to all of you all around
the world who are joining us on this
holy day. We want to say thank you and
welcome.
But let me introduce to you the family
that's taking part in the panel this
evening. We got brother Jerome.
>> Grace and peace.
>> Brother Dre.
>> Good evening.
>> Brother Julius.
>> Good evening everybody.
>> Brother James. Good evening everyone.
>> Sister Deborah,
>> good evening.
>> Brother Sean,
>> And we have the guest caller with us.
And I'm brother Cornell. Sister Deborah,
what is our first question of the
evening?
>> Uh, yes. Uh, there are several heldover
questions that will be answered first
before getting into tonight's Q&A. Uh
Shal asked, "If trash day falls on a
high Sabbath day,
would I be in violations for leaving my
trash out to be collected?" He says,
"Would that be as allowing what the
merchants attempted in Nehemiah 13
16- 21."
Now, these are two different subject
matters you talking about here. Because
if your trash day happens to fall on the
high Sabbath and you have your trash out
there prior to that high Sabbath and
that's the day that they come to collect
it, hey, that doesn't fall on you. They
out there doing what they do. But, um,
as long as you make sure it's out there
before the high Sabbath and don't put it
out there on the high Sabbath, you'll be
okay. And then you had in question about
Nehemiah the 13th chapter. Uh let's go
there. Let's go there, brother James.
You got second chronicles, you got Ezra,
and then you have Nehemiah.
Because here these people were um
polluting the Sabbath.
So let let's go in and read about that.
Nehemiah 13. And when you get there,
brother, I'd like for you to pick it up
at that verse 15 for me.
>> Okay.
Go ahead.
In those days saw I in Judas some some
threading wine presses on the Sabbath,
and bringing in sheav, and lading asses,
as also wine, grapes, and figs, and all
manner of burdens, which they brought
into Jerusalem on the Sabbath day.
And I testified against them in the day
wherein they sold vituals. So here it is
that they are polluting the Sabbath day
because they doing everything on the
Sabbath that they should have been doing
the other six days of the week. I mean
they were in there and they were dealing
with wine and grapes and figs and all
manners of burdens. So they bringing a
burden in on the Sabbath day. Go ahead,
brother.
There dwelt men of Tyrie also therein,
which brought fish, and all manners of
wear, and sold on the Sabbath unto the
children of Judah, and in Jerusalem.
>> Mhm.
>> Then I contended with the nobles of
Judah, and said unto them, "What evil
thing is this that ye do and profane the
Sabbath day?" Because Nehemiah was
telling them, right, it is evil for you
to do and to profane the Lord's Sabbath
day because he told us to keep it holy
as brother James read earlier. Keep
going, brother.
>> Did not your fathers thus? And did not
our God bring all this evil upon us and
upon this city? Yet ye bring more wrath
upon Israel by profaining the Sabbath.
>> Yeah. And it came to pass that when the
gates of Jerusalem began to be dark
before the Sabbath, I commanded that the
gates should be shut and charged that
they should not be open till after the
Sabbath.
>> Yes.
>> And some of my servants set eye at the
gates that there should no burden be
brought in on the Sabbath day. So here
you had the brother protecting the
Sabbath day like, "Hey, look, my
forefathers did that same mess and we're
not going to bring this evil in." Verse
20.
>> So all So the merchants and sellers of
all kind of wear lodged without
Jerusalem once or twice.
>> Yeah. So they hanging out the gates, you
know, trying to see if they can continue
to do what was wrong. But let's see what
they understood fully in verse 21.
Then I testified against them, and said
unto them, Why lodge ye about the wall?
If ye do so again, I will lay hands on
you. From that time forth came they no
more on the Sabbath.
>> So it looked like they understood fully
that laying hands on them, didn't he, J?
>> Oh, yeah, indeed.
>> Yeah. So that is what he had to do in
order to make sure that these people
weren't polluting the Sabbath which was
actually helping them. Sometime when
people stand up for what thus says the
Lord it helps those people around. Now
turn quickly to John 2. John 2 and3
John 2 and3 because this is dealing with
you know when you do things that is
against how it should be done. I just
want to go and show what Jesus did too
because they were making his house a
thieves and doing all that stuff back
there polluting the Sabbath day. John 2
3:13-16
for me, brother. Let's see what Jesus
did here. Go ahead.
>> And the Jews Passover was at hand. And
Jesus went up to Jerusalem and found in
the temple those that sold oxmen and
sheep and doves and the changers of
money sitting.
>> Mhm.
>> And when he had made a scourge of small
cords, he drove them all out of the
temple and the sheep and the oxen and
poured out the changers money and
overthrew the tables. So when he made
that small score of core and started to
whip them out of there, they understood
that. It's like they understood back
when Nehemiah said, I lay hands on you.
One more verse. Go ahead.
>> And said unto them that sold doves, take
these things hence. Make not my father's
house and house of merchandise.
>> So you see how they polluted the Sabbath
back then. And even the Lord was letting
it be known here how we should be
treating his sanctuary. And so
therefore, those were two questions that
you ask. First, dealing with the
garbage, you good long as it's out
before. And dealing with Nehemiah and
what Jesus did when you try and turn his
sanctuary into a house of merchandise.
That's all I got. Anybody else?
All right, we're going to leave it right
there. We hope that answered your
question as we move on to our next one.
Moving on. Ran 64 asks, "When Christ
returns back to earth, will there be a
huge earthquake all over the world? And
will Jerusalem itself be split into
three parts or the whole Israel?"
>> Will be a big show going on. Jerome,
what you got?
>> Um, well, that's that's um a two-part
question. So we going to deal with the
first part concerning um the the whole
earth.
>> Let's look at some verses and then u the
Bible going to give you the answer. So
let's go to Isaiah 24
and we going to read verse 20 and 21 and
we going to go to Revelations uh the 6th
chapter after that James.
>> Okay.
>> Isaiah 24 verse 20 and 21. You get it?
Go ahead and read.
>> It says, "The earth shall reel to and
fro like a drunkard, and shall be
removed like a cottage, and the
transgression thereof shall be heavy
upon it, and it shall fall and not rise
again."
>> Mhm. And it shall come And it shall come
to pass in that day that the Lord shall
punish the host of the high ones that
are on high and the kings of the earth
upon the earth.
>> That's good. That's good. So in that
verse 20 said, "The earth shall reel to
and fro like a drunkard and shall be
removed like a cottage. The earth abided
forever, but he going to tear it ain't
going nowhere. He but he going to tear
it up. Just picture a cottage, like a
little cottage house being towed down.
You can leave them pieces right there
and put them pieces right back together.
So, hey, the earth ain't going nowhere.
It's going to reel like a cottage. You
going to tear it down like a cottage,
but it ain't going nowhere. Okay? And
you talking about the whole earth. All
right? And the cuz the sin is heavy upon
the earth. Not in just in certain areas.
It's heavy upon the entire earth. And
the Lord going to punish the whole earth
and the sinners upon it. Okay. So, let's
go to um Revelation 6
and read verse 12-4.
When you get it, go ahead and read. It
says, "And I beheld, when he had opened
the sixth seal, and lo, there was a
great earthquake, and the sun became
black as sackcloth of hair, and the moon
became as blood."
>> And the stars of heaven fell unto the
earth, even as a fig tree casteth her
untimely figs, when she is shaken of a
mighty wind.
>> Said the stars of heaven fell to the
earth.
I imagine they ain't picking places to
fall. They just falling. Okay. Right.
>> Go ahead.
>> And the heaven departed as a scroll when
it is rolled together. And every
mountain and island were moved out of
their places.
>> Every mountain and island was moved out
of their place. Okay. They were moved
just like the book say. Every one of
them. Go ahead.
and the kings of the earth and the great
men and the rich men and the chief
captains and the mighty men and every
bond man and every free man hid
themselves in the dens and in the rocks
of the mountains and said to the
mountains and rocks fall on us and hide
us from the face of him that siteth on
the throne and from the wrath of the
lamb
>> for the great day of his wrath is come
and who shall be able to stand.
>> That's good. So, yeah, it's going to be
going on all over the earth. Okay. So,
now um let's um deal with that second
part. Could you u read that second part
Deborah for me?
>> Uh yes. and uh it states and will
Jerusalem itself be split into three
parts or the whole Israel.
I think the place you read about a city
being divided in three parts is in uh
Revelation 16. Let's go take a look at
it.
>> Okay. Uh
>> and it's not Jerusalem. Okay. But let's
go take a look at it. Revelation 16
is actually Vatican City.
Revelation 16 and 19.
And we going to do chapter 17 after
that.
>> Okay.
>> Go ahead. Read. And the great city was
divided into three parts. And the and
the cities of the nations fell, and
great Babylon came in remembrance before
God to give unto her the cup of the wine
of the fierceness of his wrath.
>> So let's go let's let's go tie that
verse that chapter n that verse 19.
Let's go tie that with Revelation 17.
Read verse 3-7. Read as quickly as you
can.
>> Okay.
>> So he carried me away in the spirit into
the wilderness. And I saw a woman sit
upon a scarlet-c colored beast full of
names of blasphemy, having seven heads
and 10 horns. And the woman was arrayed
in purple and scarlet color and decked
with gold and precious stones and
pearls, having a golden cup in her hand,
full of abominations and filthiness of
her fornication.
And upon her forehead was a name
written, mystery, Babylon the great, the
mother of harlots, and abominations of
the earth. And I saw the woman drunken
with the blood of the saints and with
the w with the blood of the martyrs of
Jesus. And when I saw her, I wondered
with great admiration.
And the angel said unto me, Wherefore
didest thou marvel? I will tell thee the
mystery of the woman, and of the beast
that carth her, which hath the seven
heads and t horns.
>> Verse n.
And here is the mind which hath wisdom.
The seven heads are seven mountains on
which the woman siteth.
>> Yeah. And this woman, she over there in
Rome.
And it's a city in Rome called Vatican
City. It sits it sits on seven
mountains. Skip down and read verse 18
about this city
which is Vatican City. Go ahead and read
verse 18. And the woman which thou
sawest is that great city which reignth
over the kings of the earth.
>> Yeah, that that's clear that that's
Vatican City. So yeah, it said a city
singular was going to be divided into
three parts and that's Vatican City.
That's all I got on.
>> All right, thank you for that. As we
move on to our next question,
>> next one. Glenn Sirius says, "I have
been reading the book Babylon Mystery
Religion and it mentioned that the
Catholic Church have thousands of
relics. Is the Shroud of Turin
just another one of these relics?"
>> All right, brother Julia, share some
light.
>> Yes, sir. Um the Catholic Church has
made the Shroud of Tan
uh a relic like they did the cross like
they do a whole lot of things. So
therefore this 14 foot long piece of
burial lineage supposed to be they claim
that it's supposed to be the burial
wrappings of Jesus Christ. All the all
the images look like some old man
that was possibly crucified because
crucifixion was very popular during
medieval ages
uh from AD 476 all the way up to the
fall of Constantinople
all the way up to the what we call the
Renaissance areas uh the reformation so
we don't know who that is you know Jesus
died at 33 years old that's not old look
at the shroud of tran
You understand? So, uh, they made it an
image, but even the Catholic Church has
not fully authenticated it because all
Israel is black, including Jesus. So,
therefore, that's that's an image of
some gentile that they came up with and
that the Catholic Church have uh what
what's the word I want to use? They have
venerated it and people devote
themselves to it, you know.
That's all I got on that. It is uh
absolutely. But you know what? I do got
something on it. Let's go to Exodus 20th
chapter. And when we get there, brother
James, look what the Lord the Lord got
all of this covered.
All of this covered. So yes, it is
another Catholic uh relic that they that
shroud they made it a relic
originated somewhere in France and now
it's it lies in uh Ly Italy over in
Italy. When did well who took it? Who
took Jesus' burial garments from
Jerusalem all the way to France and
Italy? When you get it? Exodus 24 and 5.
Exodus 20 verse4 and 5. James, go ahead.
>> Thou shalt not make unto thee any graven
image or any likeness of anything that
is in heaven above, or that is in the
earth beneath, or that is in the water
under the earth.
>> The earth beneath is anything that's
dead. Go ahead.
>> Thou shalt not bow down thyself to them,
nor serve them. For I, the Lord thy God,
am a jealous God, visiting the iniquity
of the fathers upon the children unto
the third and fourth generation of them
that hate me.
>> So the shroud of Trin is another image
of idolatry and paganism. Don't do it.
That's all I got.
>> All right. Thank you for that. Hope that
answered their question as we move on.
>> Moving on. Dad twostep says, "For su co
are we supposed to sleep in a tent or
some other dwelling?"
>> All right, brother Dre. Where should we
be laying our head at or in some other
dwelling?
>> So sukote is the feast of tabernacles or
the feast of end gathering is what we
talking about here. So, let's go over to
Leviticus 23 and we going to pick it up
at verse 39. Leviticus 23 and 39. Go
ahead, brother. When you get it, it
says, "Also, in the fifth day of the
seventh month, when ye have gathered in
the fruit of the land, ye shall keep a
feast unto the Lord seven days. On the
first day shall be a Sabbath, and on the
eighth day shall be a Sabbath.
>> So we talking about the feast of
tabernacles, which is seven days, but
the eighth day is another day. Go ahead,
brother.
>> And ye shall take you on the first day
the bows of goodly trees, branches of
palm trees, and the bowls of thick
trees, and willows of the brook. and he
shall rejoice before the Lord your God
seven days.
>> So that feast of tabernacles, seven
days, but it says, "Take palm trees,
bows of thick trees, willows of the
brook." Okay. Now, let's go over to
Nehemiah.
Nehemiah 8.
Nehemiah 8. And we're going to pick it
up at verse 14. Nehemiah 8 and 14.
Go ahead, brother. When you get it.
>> And they found written in the law which
the Lord had commanded by Moses that the
children of Israel should dwell in booth
in the feast of the seventh month.
>> Now, this feast is a feast of
tabernacles that they should dwell in
booth in the feast in the seventh month.
Go ahead, brother. and that they should
publish and proclaim in all their cities
and in Jerusalem, saying, "Go forth unto
the mount, and fetch olive branches, and
pine branches, and myrtle branches, and
palm branches, and branches of thick
trees to make boost as it is written."
>> Notice that it's very specific here.
It's talking about fetching olive
branches,
pine branches, myrtle branches,
palm branches,
willows.
Go ahead, brother.
16. So the people went forth and brought
them and made themselves boos, everyone
upon the roof of his house, and in the
courts, and in the courts of the house
of God, and in the street of the
watergate, and in the street of the gate
of Ephraim.
>> Now the question is, can you do that
today?
M
>> and you get
olive branches,
pine branches, myrtle branches as the
scriptures saying we should do willows
and make booths and then dwell in the
street and then what are you to do with
those? So, we got a lesson coming up,
the Feast of Tabernacles,
Tuesday on the 7th of October at 12
noon. And all of the detail of what this
represents and what it means will be
broke down
and you will come with full
understanding about it. But these this
is a temporary dwelling place
for man for 7 days
and after that on the eighth day man is
no more that. Now let's go over to
Zechariah 14. We're going to look at one
place there and that'll be it. Zechariah
14 and pick it up at 16. When you get
there, go ahead, brother.
And it shall come to pass that everyone
that is left of all the nations, which
came against Jerusalem, shall even go up
from year to year to worship the King,
the Lord of Hosts, and to keep the feast
of tabernacles.
>> Go ahead. And it shall be that whosoever
will not come up of all the families of
the earth unto Jerusalem to worship the
king the Lord of hosts even upon them
shall be no rain. So in the kingdom the
the in in in in the seventh day in the
Lord Jesus kingdom the the feast of
tabernacles will be kept
and it will be kept in the land and we
will do it right. So on your own read
Exodus I mean Ezekiel 20 and 40 and
it'll bless you as pertaining to that.
But I would say again come keep the
feast of tabernacles. October 7th, 12
noon and you will get a full breakdown
of all of this. That's all I got.
>> All right, brother. So, good light there
as we move on to our next question.
>> Next question. Kylie Parker says, "Other
than Luke 18 verse 11, is the spirit of
infirmity
mentioned elsewhere in the Bible? Does
this show that physical illness is only
caused by angels?
>> All right. So, I know they mentioned
that Luke 18 and verse 11 about the
spirit of infirmity mentioned um caller
would take it from there.
>> Go read it.
>> Luke 18 and 11.
>> Okay. It says, "The Pharisee stood and
prayed thus with himself. God, I thank
thee that I am not as other men are,
extortioners, unjust, adulterers, or
even as this publican.
>> I don't see nothing in there that speaks
about spiritual infirmities, our angels
causing people to get sick." So, whoever
answer the question, asked a question,
get the right scripture and then come
back. That's all I have to say.
>> All right,
we're going to move on to our next
question.
>> Next question. Uh, Eric Masala says,
"Brother Jerome,
you mentioned before there are two sets
of the 144,000.
Could you explain that further, please?"
>> All right. this question. Brother
Jerome,
what you got, brother?
>> Well, in um Revelations the uh 7th
chapter,
uh they going to be flesh and blood.
When the Lord come on the scene, they
going to still be flesh and blood, but
the 144 that's in Revelation the 14th
chapter, they going to make the first
resurrection. Now, I'm going to go into
a little detail try to show this to you.
All right. So, uh
and let's go to the seventh chapter of
Revelations
and we going to pick it up at the uh 14.
We going to skip
>> the 14 verse.
>> Yeah. because it's we we know it's
talking about the 144
uh thousand in verses 4 through8. All
right.
>> Okay.
>> So, let's go right into the 14th um
verse and we going to skip after that.
Okay. Read verse 14.
>> It says, "And I said unto him, sir, thou
knowest. And he said to me, "These are
they which came out of great tribulation
and have washed their robes and made
them white in the blood of the lamb."
Okay? Now, these went through great
tribulation. Okay? And they did they
they you know they started taking in
some some believing in in the Lord at
that point. All right? But they didn't
believe enough to make the first
resurrection.
They didn't really start really
believing until they were caught up in
this great tribulation. All right? So,
they converted during the great
tribulation, but not enough to make the
first resurrection. So, by the time the
Lord come, they going to still be flesh
and blood. All right? So, skip and read
verse 17.
It says, "For the Lamb which is in the
midst of the throne shall feed them and
shall lead them unto living fountains of
waters, and God shall wipe wipe away all
tears from their eyes."
>> Now, we just read earlier
uh in Zechariah, I think it was the 14th
chapter, the brother quoted that we
going to have to keep the feast of
tabernacles.
Even the people that didn't make that
first resurrection,
they going to have to come up from year
to year and keep all the feasts. All
right? And so
this 17th verse is letting you know
those that didn't make that first
resurrection, but the Lord put that seal
on them. You know, when they wash their
robes, in the blood of the lamb, they
flesh and blood. And they going to be
coming up to keep the feast, the
tabernacle. They going to be coming to
keep all the feast, but they still going
to be flesh and blood. Okay. So now
let's go to Ezekiel 46.
Okay,
>> let's show you that these people going
to be coming up.
Ezekiel 46.
I was almost there. There you go. And we
going to pick it up at verse one. Read
it to the three and we're going to skip.
>> Okay,
>> this is the Lord is back at this time.
The Lord is back on this earth. He set
up here in his temple in Jerusalem.
Okay, just like we read in Revelation,
they going to worship before the Lord.
All right, so go ahead and read that
1-3.
>> It says, "Thus sayeth the Lord God, the
gate of the inner court that lookth
towards the east shall be shut the six
working days, but on the Sabbath it
shall be open, and in the day of the new
moon it shall be open. And the prince
shall enter by the way of the porch of
that gate without and shall stand by the
post of the gate. And the priest shall
prepare his burnt offering and his peace
offerings. And he shall worship at the
threshold of the gate. Then he shall go
forth, but the gate shall not be shut
until the evening.
>> Yeah. So he going to be worshiping the
Lord, too. This prince right here. But
that's another lesson. Keep reading.
Likewise, the people of the land shall
worship at the door of this gate before
the Lord in the Sabbaths and in the new
moons.
>> Mhm. I want you to skip to verse eight,
read it to the nine.
>> And when the prince shall enter, he
shall go in by the way of the porch of
that gate, and he shall go forth by the
way thereof. But when the people of the
land shall come before the Lord in the
solemn feast, he that enterth in by the
way of the north gate to worship shall
go out by the way of the south gate.
>> And he that enterth by the way of the
south gate shall go forth by the way of
the north gate. He shall not return by
the way of the gate whereby he came in,
but shall go forth over against it.
Okay. So, the 144,000 that was in that
Revelation 17th chapter, they flesh and
blood, they among these people that's
come before the Lord to worship before
him. Okay? During the feast and on the
Sabbath days. All right. Now, uh let's
go to chapter 47 right quick.
>> Okay.
>> Read verse 21 to 23.
>> Okay. It says, "So shall ye divide this
land unto you according to the tribes of
Israel. And it shall come to pass that
ye shall divide it by lot for an
inheritance unto you, and to the
strangers that sjourn among you."
>> Strangers that sjourn among you.
>> So they they going to come up and
worship before the Lord too
>> like we just read
>> in 46th chapter. Keep read
>> which shall be got children among you
and they shall be unto you as born in
the country among the children of
Israel. They shall they shall have
inheritance with you among the tribes of
Israel.
>> Those are the ones that dwell in that's
that dwell among Israel. Okay, go ahead.
And it shall come to pass that in what
tribe the stranger joinneth there shall
ye give
him his inheritance sayeth the Lord God.
All right. Uh
like like like like brother boy was say
you know he wants to make make full
proof of this thing. So I I got to read
that 48. Let's go to 48. Chapter 48 and
read verse 29-31.
>> Okay. Is
>> read quickly. Read it quickly.
>> This is the land which ye shall divide
by lot unto the tribes of Israel for
inheritance, and these are their
portions, sayeth the Lord God. And these
are the goings out of the city of the
north side, 4,500
measures. And the gates of the city
shall be after the names of the tribes
of Israel. Three gates northward. One
gate of Reuben, one gate of Judah, one
gate of Levi.
>> That's good. Skip down and read verse 3.
Skip down. Read verse 35.
>> It was round about 18,000 measures. And
the name of the city from that day shall
be, the Lord is there.
>> Yeah. Cuz they going to be worshiping
for the Lord. these flesh and blood
people including 144,000 in Revelation
the 7th chapter. All right. Now, let's
go to Revelations 14. This going to be
the last place. Revelations 14 and read
verse one because that's talking about
the 144,000 that made their first
resurrection. They not among these flesh
and blood people, nor are they uh among
the 144,000 in Revelation chapter 7.
That's flesh and blood. These 144,000
are spirit beings. They made the first
resurrection. Okay. Revelation 14:E1.
Go ahead.
>> And I and I looked and lo, a lamb stood
on the mount Zion. And with him 140 and
4,000 having his father's name written
in their foreheads.
>> They got the father's name written their
forehead. Come on.
>> And I heard a voice.
>> Go ahead. You go ahead. Yeah, go ahead.
>> And I And I heard a voice from heaven as
the voice of many waters and as the
voice of a great thunder. And I heard
the voice of harpers harping with their
harps.
>> That's good. That's That's enough.
That's all I got on that.
>> You on mute, brother Cornell.
>> All right. Thank you for that, brother.
Hope that answered that question. Next
question, sister.
>> Next question. Red Wolf says the staff
is mentioned many times throughout the
Bible. Is it symbolic in a way
represents a brotherhood or Hebrew
Israelite nation?
And Judges 6 verse 21 and Genesis 38
verse8 is given.
>> All right. Concerning his staff, what do
we say, brother Julius?
The staff depend upon the situation is
used as in for many purposes uh for
weapons for traveling over terrain uh to
perform miracles or also to identify
let's go to that Judges 21. Let's we got
a few scriptures to go over here real
quick.
>> Okay.
>> Judges 21 and verse 6. This is in the
days of uh Gideon.
>> You mean Judges 6 and 21?
>> Judges 6 and 21. Thank you.
>> Okay.
It says, "Then the angel of the Lord put
forth the end of the staff that was in
his hand and touched the flesh and the
unleavened cakes, and there rose up fire
out of the rock and consumed the flesh
and the unleavened cakes. Then the angel
of the Lord departed out of his sight."
>> So now that was the angel of the Lord
that did a miracle with his staff uh in
front of uh Gideon. Let's sit down.
Let's go to what's the other scriptures?
>> Genesis 38 38 and 18.
>> Genesis 38 and 18.
When you get it, my brother James, go
ahead and read it.
>> It says, "And he said, what pledge shall
I give thee?" And she said, "Thy signate
and thy bracelets and thy staff that is
in thine hand." and he gave it her and
came in unto her and she conceived by
him.
>> So now that was a token for uh the
purpose of uh a I guess a down payment
or something uh with Judah and Tamar. So
it was used uh for that purpose
and it's a signate of his ring. Let's go
to another place. Let's go to Genesis
32.
The question is, a better question is
why did these people have staffs?
Nothing had nothing to do with just the
nation of Israel. Whole lot of nations
had staffs. Genesis 32, read verse 9 and
10. Let's see who else had a staff. Go
ahead. And Jacob said, "Oh God of my
father Abraham, and God of my father
Isaac, the Lord which saith unto me,
Return unto thy country and to thy
kindred, and I will deal with I will
deal well with thee."
>> Uh-huh. I am not worthy of the least of
all the mercies and of all the truth
which thou hast showed unto thy servant.
For with my staff I passed over this
Jordan and now I am become two bands. So
now he used that staff, Jacob did, to uh
to go over rough terrain or to cross a
river, to help cross a river, just like
a man uses a walking uh stick or a cane
uh as a third leg for support. It could
also be used uh Israel was a wondering
people. They had flocks and herds to
pull them, to protect them, to uh pull
them back and keep everything in order.
But why did they have these staffs?
Let's go to Numbers the 17th chapter.
Numbers the 17th chapter. And I got one
place after this. Numbers the 17th
chapter, brother James, and pick it up
at verse one and two. Look what the Lord
told Moses. Because if you look at the
Ten Commandments,
Pharaoh gave Moses a staff. We can't
read that. What do the book say?
And the Lord spake unto Moses, saying,
Speak unto the children of Israel, and
take of every one of them a rod
according to the house of their fathers.
>> Go ahead.
>> of all their princes according to the
house of their fathers, 12 rods.
>> Write thou every man's name upon his
rod.
>> So now that was used to identify what
tribe you came from. That's why the
staff served many purposes to identify
the um uh house you came from. Skip down
to verse 68 quickly. Go ahead, brother.
>> And Moses spake unto the children of
Israel. And every one of their princes
gave him a rod of peace. For each prince
won according to their father's houses,
even 12 rods, and the rods of Aaron was
among their rods.
>> Yes.
And Moses laid up the rods before the
Lord in the tabernacle of witness.
>> And it came to pass that on the marorrow
Moses went into the tabernacle of
witness and behold the rod of Aaron for
the house of Levi was budded and brought
forth buds and bloom blossoms and
yielded almonds.
>> So in that case they were used Aaron's
rod was used to perform a miracle. My
last place Zechariah the 8th chapter.
What about when the Lord returns,
sisters, them brothers,
and he dwell among this flesh and blood
man?
Zechariah 8
and verse4.
Zechariah 8 and verse4. What the book
say?
>> Thus sayeth the Lord of hosts.
>> Know what? Pick it up at verse three cuz
we got to show that he's back now. Go
ahead. Thus sayeth the Lord, I am
returned unto Zion, and will dwell in
the midst of Jerusalem, and Jerusalem
shall be called a city of truth, and the
mountain of the Lord of hosts, the holy
mountain.
>> Yes.
>> Thus said the Lord of hosts, there shall
yet all men and all women dwell in the
streets of Jerusalem, and every man with
his staff in his hand for very age. So
therefore, sisters and brothers, this
staff serves many purposes, even from
the ancient times, even to the return of
the Lord. That's all I got, brother
Cornell.
>> Yes, sir.
>> By the way, the Lord said he going to
rule the earth with a rod of iron.
[Music]
>> Yes, sir. Moses stretched his rod across
and split the sea with the power of God,
didn't he?
>> Performing mer uh to show the power of
God. Performing mercies, miracles. Thank
you, brother. Yes sir.
>> Can I add
>> Yes, sir. Guest call.
>> Everybody, all the males carried staffs.
>> Okay. Some use them for something. He
said, but it was just like having a
third arm. All all the males carry
staff.
>> Yes, sir.
>> Okay.
>> All right. That's all I got.
>> Thank you.
>> All right. Well, we hope that answers
your question, Sister Deborah. Next
question with a time check.
>> Yes. Moving on. The time is 8:15.
D1 Dikis asks, "Why is there an Old and
New Testament?"
>> All right, Brother Dre. So, we got Old
Testament and we got a New Testament.
Why is that?
>> Yeah. Man gave you Old Testament from
Genesis to Malachi and then uh New
Testament, Matthew to Revelation. But
let's see what the books say about why
uh that this is the Bible. But let's go
to uh second Timothy
3 and we're going to read verses 16 and
17. Why are we given this Bible? Let's
read it. Go ahead, brother.
All scripture is given by inspiration of
God and is profitable for doctrine, for
reprove, for correction, for instruction
in righteousness,
>> that the man of God may be perfect,
thoroughly furnished unto all good
works.
>> So this word of God furnishes us. It is
g it is inspired by God and is
profitable for doctrine, reproof,
correction, and instruction in
righteousness. Let's go over to Romans
the 15th chapter. And we're just going
to read one verse there. Romans 15 and
verse 4. Go ahead, brother. For
whatsoever things were written before
time were written for our learning, that
we through patience and comfort of the
scriptures might have hope.
>> Yes, sir.
>> That's what this this that's that's what
this scripture is for. And it gives us
that if we read it, study it, give our
minds to it. That's all I got, brother.
>> Yes, sir.
>> Hey, brother. Uh, brother Dre, can we
read that uh Isaiah 82 to show that we
we need to have them both?
>> Yep.
>> Absolutely.
>> Old and new. Ain't no splitting them up.
>> You know, some people I'm Old Testament
Christian. I'm a New Testament
Christian. I only keep the first five
books. I this, I that. But what does
Isaiah 8 and 20 say? And then, Brother
Dre, if you got something else on that,
go ahead. Um, Brother Jay,
>> why don't you Hey, brother James, read
16.
Read 16 and then read 20.
>> Okay.
>> Yes, sir.
>> Verse 16 says, "Bind up the testimony.
Seal the law among my disciples."
>> Verse 20 says, "To the law and to the
testimony. If they speak not according
to this word, it is because there is no
light in them."
>> That's right. You need both. a a good
householder bring forth things new and
old. Jesus said
>> that's right.
>> Yeah. To the law and to the testimony.
Thank you, brother Cornell.
>> Hey, brother Dre and brother Cornell.
>> Yes, sir.
>> Just one more spot and we can we can we
could probably move on. Psalm 68 and
verse 11. It's one thing we got to
remember.
>> Psalm 68 and verse 11. And that's all I
got.
>> Okay. Psalm 68 and11 says, "The Lord
gave the word. Great was the company of
those that published it."
>> That's right. You see you see all of the
the joy in this word and and those that
have it and great is the company of
those that publish it. And that's what
we doing now.
>> I hope that helped. That's all I got,
bro.
>> All right. That was some good word
there. As we move on to our next
question,
>> next question. Sir Reed said, "I stopped
going to Sunday church about three years
ago and started doing my own seeking and
joining IOG
online service, online sabbath service.
But my mother keeps telling me about
fellowship. Basically telling me church
is important.
But there is no church that teach the
truth like IOG.
Am I I'm from Ghana. What to do?
>> All right. Well, we we glad that you
found the online services and uh I agree
I agree with your mother
because you get the pure uncut word of
God when you're dealing with the Israel
of God all the time. And so also uh what
you get when you're dealing with the
Israel of God too. Let let's go into uh
Ecclesiastes 12 because this is
something that um it's hard to find
amongst a lot of places but you can
guarantee to get it at the Israel of
God. Let's go into the Ecclesiastes 12
and let's pick it up brother. Let's read
that verse 9 and 10.
Ecclesiastes 9 and10 or verse I mean
chapter 12 verse 9 and 10 says and
moreover because the preacher was wise
he still taught the people knowledge.
Yay he gave good heed and sought out and
set in order many proverbs
>> because you gota have you gotta have
somebody that's able to teach you this
word of God and able to give it to you
pure and uncut. Keep reading. The
preacher sought to find out acceptable
words, and that which was written was
upright, even words of truth.
>> Uh-huh.
>> The words of the wise are as gold, as
nails fastened by the masters of
assemblies, which are given from one
shepherd.
>> Oh, this word is given from one
shepherd. Just like we just got through
expounding on the Old and the New
Testament, it is given from one
shepherd.
And the reason that we get that pure
uncut word of God too is to give you a
fighting chance in that verse 13 and 14.
Go ahead.
>> Let us hear the conclusion of the whole
matter. Fear God and keep his
commandments for this is the whole duty
of man. So, brother James, if you're at
a place where it tell you where you
don't have to keep the commandments,
that's the wrong place, ain't it?
>> That's that it is. Yes, sir.
>> Read that next verse.
>> For God shall bring every work into
judgment with every secret thing,
whether it be good or whether it be
evil.
>> Yeah. So, we are all about salvation and
teaching you how to get it and you can
get it pure and uncut. And your mom is
giving you some good advice there. So, I
think it would behoove you to continue
to stay tuned in with us. Guest caller,
go right ahead.
>> I got to disagree with you. Only mom
giving good advice. You didn't listen to
what the question
>> read,
>> right? Mom want him to go to church. But
again, uh he says, "But my mother keeps
telling me about fellowship."
basically telling me church is important
but there is no church that teach the
truth like IG
I'm from Ghana what to do
>> now and I agree with the brother and
disagree with his mother because they
ain't teaching
>> and you going and and and uh fellowship
with them what you're doing is you are
helping them heads up a lie.
Now, it is good to congregate. The Lord
tell you in in the 23rd chapter of
Leviticus that you should have a holy
convocation on the Sabbath day. But if
you can't have one in person
without going and dealing with lies,
then the brother's doing the best thing.
He's having a holy convocation with us
on the uh internet online.
So you correct, brother. If they ain't
teaching the truth and they teaching a
lie, don't go there. But if you do,
you're supporting it.
Your best move is what you're doing now.
Be at home and fellowship with us on the
internet. That's all I got to say.
>> Okay. I misinterpreted that cuz I was
definitely in agreement with there is no
church that teach the truth like the
Israel of God. Okay.
All right. We hope that that answered
your question there as we move on to our
next
>> moving on. Andre Jr. asks, "Is chicken
skin considered fat? Are you able to use
medication pills that contains animal
fat or unclean animals?"
Leviticus 7 verse 24 is given.
>> All right. So, talking about the chicken
skin and are you able to use um
medication that consists of unclean
animals using Leviticus 7 and verse 24?
James, let's go there.
>> Okay, I'm there
>> and go ahead and read that and the guest
caller take it from there.
>> Okay. Leviticus 7 and 24 says, "And the
fat of the beast that dieth of itself,
and the fat of that which is torn with
beasts may be used in any other use, but
ye shall in no wise eat of it."
>> Why don't you back up a couple verses
and start and read that?
>> Okay. You want me to start at 22?
Yep, that's a good place.
>> Verse 22 says, "And the Lord spake unto
Moses, saying, Speak unto the children
of Israel, saying, Ye shall eat no
manner of fat, of ox or of sheep, or of
goat. And the fat of the beast that
dietth of itself, and the fat of that
which is torn with beasts, may be used
in any other use, but ye shall in no
wise eat of it.
Now that the the beast that they name
are clean beast,
so you can't eat of it, but yeah, you
can use it for other means, probably
medication, but you just can't eat it
like the Lord said. But they was talking
about clean beast, not unclean beast.
And as far as chicken skin being fat,
every time I see chicken skin, it's
called chicken skin. It don't say
chicken fat. That's all I have to say.
>> All right. And so those medications call
it sometimes they come in just unclean
casings. like some pills are are
unclean, but they can still take it if
that's all that's available or what
should they do in that case?
>> The Bible The Bible was talking about
clean beasts. Anything beyond that is uh
uh uh is is adding to it.
>> Okay.
All right. We're going to leave it there
and move on to our next question.
>> One second. Bible. Okay.
>> I'm sorry. Repeat that.
>> I said just like we said in the
beginning, we think we we dealing with
things that's written in the King James
version of the Bible.
>> Right.
>> Anything beyond that, we don't have
nothing to comment on.
>> That's correct. All right. Moving on to
our next question.
>> Next question. Surely SW asks is the son
of predition and the antichrist the
and the antichrist the only entities
talked about in the prophecy that is
supposed to come.
>> All right, we dealing here with the son
of predition and antichrist. Guess call
them.
>> I don't use the word antichrist. I call
beast and false prophet. But the
question you ask, I have to ask you a
question in order for you to answer and
and uh uh uh and that is
you know uh uh when you say the only
thing that is to come. Question I want
to ask you is
this is uh
the things to come after what?
You got a whole lot of prophecies that
got to take place.
So you got to be specific. You can't
just say uh uh uh talking about uh uh in
the prophet that is supposed to come. To
come after what?
I think you need to be more specific.
That's all I have to say.
>> Correct. You're welcome to resubmit
your question. All right, Sister
Deborah, moving on to our next one.
>> Yes. Uh, why is the day of atonement
necessary?
>> Why is the day of atonement necessary?
Guess callum.
>> Why don't you go to Leviticus 23rd
chapter and read it?
>> Okay. Where would you like for me to
start, sir?
>> At the day of uh uh uh start first at
Leviticus 23
one and two and skip down and read and
uh uh read verse four.
>> Okay. It says, "And the Lord spake unto
Moses, saying, speak unto the children
of Israel, and say unto them concerning
the feast of the Lord, which you shall
proclaim to be holy convocations, even
these are my feast. Verse
four says, "These are the feasts of the
Lord, even holy convocations, which ye
shall proclaim in their seasons."
>> Now, skip down to the day of atonement.
>> 26.
>> Yes. And verse 26 says, "And the Lord
spake unto Moses, saying,
>> also on the 10th day of this seventh
month, there shall be a day of
atonement. It shall be in
>> holy cut.
>> Let me cut.
>> It is necessary because the Lord said do
we.
>> Yes, sir.
>> That's all I got to say.
>> Okay.
>> All right.
All right. We're going to leave it right
there, Sister Deborah, as we take a step
into new territory.
>> Uh, yes. We are now into tonight's Q&A
for Wednesday, October the 1st, 2025.
Queen Candace Awake
asks, "Would playing biblical games
after the day of atonement lesson be
considered doing our own pleasures?"
>> All right, let's open up some of these
questions to the to the panel.
If you're playing some biblical games on
your phone or laptop,
after the lesson of atonement. Is that
considered as doing your own pleasure?
That's that's a solemn that's a solemn
assembly.
>> And then and all and all the feasts are
are are solemn, but that's a solemn
assembly. What's solemn of about paying
gains? What you should do is be reading
your Bible and praying God and ask him
to forgive you for the many sins that
you done s the whole year up until the
day of atonement.
>> Amen.
>> Yep.
>> So
>> yeah, put that aside and put all your
focus on God.
Okay, moving on to our next question.
>> Uh next question. MJ uh MJ
asks, "How do you know when the Lord is
chasing you?"
All right. How do you know when the Lord
is chasening you? Open to the panel.
>> Cuz the Lord say chasing those whom he
love. Correct. So that can be a good
thing.
Are you doing something that's out of
order to bring the Lord's upon you?
>> You know, we always said if if the Lord
is or if you feel like the Lord is
afflicting you, maybe we have to do a
sin check.
>> Let's check our behavior.
>> But again, but again too, you don't
know. What did Jesus say when the wall
fell on some people and killed them?
>> He said this thing happened time and
chance happened to everybody.
>> Simple as that. So, how you going to
know?
>> Yeah.
So,
all right. Next question.
>> Next question. Randy Sims says, it says
all the Israelites had first names. So,
where did Jesus get his last name? Why
do they say Jesus Christ?
Please explain.
>> Christ is not his last name. Christ is a
title. It means anointed one. All Israel
last name was Israel.
Because when he when the Lord when when
Jacob answered to the angel, he said,
"You shall no longer be called Jacob.
Your name shall be called Israel.
Your name." So when he adopted us, we
took on his name Israel
just like the Muslims do it after they
after they found Jesse Muhammad, Sally
Muhammad, Xavier Muhammad.
That's all I got.
>> Yep.
All right.
Christ is the anointed one. Next
question.
>> Next question. Edward Bobber says, "If
the dead knows nothing, why do people
say they talk to their dead loved ones?
And who are they talking with? And are
we as humans possessed by evil spirits
only from our own lust and bad doctrine?
>> It seemed like they got quite a bit on
that question there. So, can you break
it down um to the first question first?
>> Yes. If the dead knows nothing, why do
people say they talk to their dead loved
ones?
>> Because they lying.
>> Yep.
>> And the next question and of it is who
are they talking with? Who are they
talking with? And why are we as humans
possessed
by evil spirits
only from our own lust and bad doctrine?
>> First thing is
they ain't talking with the dead ones.
Even they talking with themselves.
Then what do you mean possessed by evil
spirits?
Everybody have good and bad thoughts.
That don't mean they possessed by evil
spirits.
Why would the Lord allow that?
That's all I got to say. Yeah. And that
uh that Ecclesiastes 9 and 10 say,
"Whatsoever thy hand findeth to do, do
it with all thy might. For there is no
work, nor device, nor knowledge, nor
wisdom in the grave with it thou goest."
So ain't no talking coming from them who
have perished. Job tell Job tell the
14th chapter that once a person die they
will not be awaken out of their sleep.
>> That's right.
>> Yep. All right. Next question.
>> Next question. Jennifer Love
says, "Could you explain Zechariah 14
16- 19?
Is this future?
>> All right. Zechariah 14
16-19.
>> Yes.
>> All right. Why don't we go there,
brother James?
And when you get there, brother, pick it
up
at that verse 16.
>> Okay. It says, "And it shall come to
pass that everyone that is left of all
the nations which came against Jerusalem
shall even go up from year to year to
worship the King, the Lord of Hosts, and
to keep the feast of tabernacles."
>> Future. Go ahead.
>> Yep. And it shall be that whoso will not
come up of all the families of the earth
unto Jerusalem to worship the king, the
Lord of hosts, even upon them shall be
no rain.
>> Future.
And if the family of Egypt go not up and
come not, that have no rain, there shall
be the plague, wherewith the Lord will
smite the heathen that come not up to
the keep the feast of tabernacles.
>> Future,
>> this shall be the punishment of Egypt,
and the punishment of all nations that
come not up to keep the keep the feast
of tabernacles.
M
>> now let's show you why we know it's the
future. Go back to Zechariah 14. Start
reading at verse one.
>> Yes sir.
>> It says verse one says behold the day of
the Lord cometh and thy spoil shall be
divided in the midst of thee.
For for I will gather all nations
against Jerusalem to battle, and the
city shall be taken, and the houses
rifled, and the women ravished, and half
of the city shall go forth into
captivity, and the residue of the people
shall not be cut off from the city.
Amen.
>> Then shall the Lord go forth and fight
against those nations when he fought in
the day of battle.
And his feet shall stand in that day
upon the Mount of Olives, which is
before Jerusalem on the east, and the
Mount of Olives shall cleave in the
midst thereof toward the east, and
toward the west. And there shall be a
very great valley and half of the
mountain shall remount.
Now the mount of olives is on the earth
is in Jerusalem over there.
>> Yes sir.
>> And he's back on earth. Go ahead.
>> And half of the mountain shall remove
toward the north and half of it toward
the south.
>> Go ahead.
>> And ye shall flee to the valley of the
mountains. For the valley of the
mountain shall reach unto Ael. Yay, ye
shall flee like as ye fled from before
the earthquake in the days of Uzziah,
king of Judah. And the Lord my God shall
come and all the saints with thee.
>> So that mean that this time the Lord
going to come, his feet going to stand
on Mount Olives and he going to come and
all of the saints going to be with him.
That's all of the people in the first
resurrection.
Get down to verse nine.
>> And the Lord shall be king over all the
earth. In that day shall there be one
Lord and his name one.
>> So that's why all the nations going to
be going to Jerusalem to keep the
tabernacle and to worship before the
Lord because he will he is back on the
earth. So you could have answered that
question yourself. How's these people
going to go to Jerusalem and worship the
Lord in Jerusalem and he haven't come
yet? That's our own future.
That's all I have to say.
>> All right. Hope that answers your
question as we move on to our next one.
>> Our next question. Time out. Houston uh
says, "Why would God ban idols then
command Moses to build net Ned Houston?
>> Then command Moses to what Deborah.
>> Okay. Uh
>> serpent.
>> Yeah.
Serpent.
>> Yeah. Ned Houston. So why would God ban
idols then command Moses to build Nan
Houston?
>> He gave it as a as a token of their
faith.
>> That's what it is. You understand? They
mourn against God and they and every
time they get in trouble, they go to
God. Oh Lord, get us out of it. He get
them out of it. Then they go get it on
again. So, so when he come and his
snakes are sleep doing biting them, then
he I tell you what,
it's obvious they ain't believe in me.
So, what you do is you put a snake on a
stick. If you get bit by a snake, if you
look on the stick, then uh on a snake,
then you live. If you don't look up on a
snake, then you die. In other words,
like Judas just said, is to is to make
them have some faith.
But then when the people started
worshiping
this thing, then the Lord had it
destroyed.
>> That's right.
>> So that's what it was. Make them show
their faith.
That's all I have to say.
>> All right, we'll move on to our next
question.
>> Next question. Malikica Bang uh says,
"Brothers, can you please explain how
King David and Jesus shared a lineage,
I've been doing some research, but I
don't understand how Mary is connected
to King David or how Joseph is
connected.
All right.
>> They came out of They came out of the
lineage.
It's all that simple.
>> Read that Luke on your Read Luke 3 on
your own.
>> Go read it to him.
>> Okay.
Luke 3, you want to start at verse one?
>> Go ahead.
Now in the 15th year of the reign of
Tiberius Caesar, Pontius Pilate being
governor of Judea and Herod being
tetrarch of Galilee and his brother
Philip Traarch of Ita and of the re
religion of Trachanistas
and Linius and Tetrarch of Abene.
Annis and Sephus being the high priest.
The word of God came unto John the son
of Zachcharias in the wilderness. And he
came into all the country about Jordan,
preaching the baptism of repentance for
the remission of sins.
>> You can skip down to verse uh 23 and
begin that on own on your own. You read
the whole thing, but this is the
lineage. Read verse 23. And Jesus
himself began to be about 30 years of
age, being as was supposed the son of
Joseph, which was the son of Heli,
which was the son of Mat, which was the
son of Levi, which was the son of
>> skip down, James, to verse uh 31,
>> which was 30. Verse 30,
>> which was the son of Simeon, which was
the son of Judah, which was the son of
Joseph, which was the son of Jo Jonah,
which was the son of Elakim, which was
the son of Malia, which was the son of
Menan, which was the son of Mata, which
was the son of Nathan, which was the son
of David.
>> So now that's David right there. Then
you read verse 34,
>> which was the son of Jacob, which was
the son of Isaac, which was the son of
Abraham, which was the son of Thor,
which was the son of Nor.
>> Jump down to verse 38,
>> which was the son of Enos, which was the
son of Seth, which was the son of Adam,
which was the son of God.
>> So that's how you track Jesus' lineage
lineage. You can also read it in
Chronicles. But that's how you track
through uh genealogies through the
lineages.
>> That's all I got. Quil.
>> All right, we'll leave it right there as
we move on to our next question with a
time check.
>> Yes, the time is 8:46.
Uh Kylie Parker
has given the correct uh scripture. Uh
her other scripture was Luke 18 verse 11
and that had nothing to do with um in uh
the spirit of infirmities that was
mentioned in the uh Bible. So she gives
now she says Luke 13
verse 11 is the spirit of infirmity
mentioned elsewhere in the Bible. Does
this show that physical illness is
caused by angels? And she says, "Sorry
for the wrong scripture."
>> All right.
No problem there. Luke 13. Let's go to
Luke 13 and then pick it up when you get
there, brother. And then verse
>> 11.
>> Okay. It says, "And behold, there was a
woman which had a spirit of infirmity 18
years and was bold together and could in
no wise lift up herself."
>> All that mean she was just sick.
Okay.
>> Mhm.
Read some more. Verse 12 says, "And when
Jesus saw her, he called her to him and
said unto her,"Woman,
thou art loose from thine infirmity."
>> Uhhuh.
>> And he laid his hands on her, and
immediately she was made straight and
glorified God.
>> It means she was sick. another place
they about is another woman had an
informity too and she had been had
doctors and everything else and they
couldn't heal her so she touched Jesus
garment
and that healed her that's all it mean
she was just sick that didn't have
nothing to do with her being possessed
by by a a devil
but read you see if you can read
something that show that keep read
>> and the rule ruler of the synagogue
answered with indignation, because that
Jesus had healed on the Sabbath day, and
said unto the people, "There are six
days in which men ought to work, and
them therefore come and be healed, and
not on the Sabbath day."
The the Lord then answered him and said,
"Thou hypocrite, do not each one of you
on the Sabbath loose his ox or his ass
from the stall, and lead him away to
watering? And ought not this woman,
being a daughter of Abraham, whom Satan
hath bound, lo, these 18 years, be
loosed from this bound on the Sabbath
day."
See that bow didn't come on her
particular you know that sickness you
know when it came on
>> when Adam and Eve ate from the wrong
tree.
>> Yes sir.
>> So that binding of Satan start when our
forefathers when our mother and father
listen to him instead of listen to God.
That's when sick come in.
You just don't
>> don't run around jumping people,
>> right? So she asked it is illness caused
by angels.
>> Illness is caused it was is called by
sin and the sin was committed in the
garden of Eden
>> about for death.
>> You know cuz Paul had a condition and he
prayed to the Lord and Lord wouldn't
heal him.
Did somebody go read that?
If you can look it up. All right. Search
mode for that. Should be coming up with
it very shortly here.
Um,
let's see here.
That's um
first Peter. No, not first Peter.
>> Second Corinthians 12.
>> Yeah.
>> Seven.
>> Okay.
>> 2 Corinthians 12:7 says, "An least I
should be exalted above measure through
the abundance of the revelations. There
was given to me a thorn in the flesh,
the messenger of Satan to buffet me,
least I should be exalted above measure.
For this thing I besought the Lord
thrice, that it might depart from me.
And he said unto me, my grace is
sufficient for thee, for my strength is
made perfect in weakness. Most gladly,
therefore, will I rather glory in my
infirmities than that the power of
Christ may rest upon me.
So, the whole thing is why wouldn't uh
Jesus heal Paul?
Going to let him be running around
possessed by a devil. If he was arrest
possessed by a devil, then how could you
write all them books and write all the
word of God that goes back to the Garden
of Eden?
We wouldn't have had no sickness
and Adam and Eve listened to God and
didn't communicate with Satan.
That's all I have to say.
>> All right, we're going to move on to our
next question as time is a ticking. What
do you say, Julia?
I need to make an addition to the answer
that I just gave pertaining cuz her
question was also how she don't
understand how Mary could be uh uh uh
considered uh a relative of David. Could
we go to Luke the 1st chapter and read
two verses?
>> You said Luke.
>> Okay, that's um
>> that's uh that was the question before.
That's not the question we're on,
>> right? That was a question before and I
want to give her because she asks how
could she doesn't understand how a Mary
could be connected with David. And we
going to show her here. Luke 1, read
verse 26 and 27. Mhm. Luke 1 26 says,
"In the sixth month, the angel Gabriel
was sent from God unto a city of Galilee
named Za Nazareth to a virgin espouseed
to a man whose name was Joseph of the
house of David. And the virgin's name
was Mary."
>> Because they came through the lineage of
David. They were Jews. David was a Jew
of the tribe of Judah.
That's how it happens. I hope that
helped.
>> And they never used the female as
lineage.
>> The man carried the seed.
>> You go.
>> All right.
>> You didn't have even though that wasn't
David's seed, still it come by way I
mean Joseph's seed, it come by way of
Joseph's wife.
>> Yes, sir.
>> Don't have to say.
>> All right. Next question.
>> Okay. So, I want to uh clear that up
because I don't want anyone to be
confused. The question that you uh
you're uh
dealing with was from Malikite Bank that
asked that she couldn't uh find the
lineage or research or understand about
uh King David and Joseph in connection
with uh understanding Mary with a
connection of King David and Jo uh
Joseph. Now after that we talked about
Kylie and she was asking about how does
uh physical illness how is it caused and
she wanted to know was it caused by
angels and it was discussed it was
through our parents Adam and Eve. So
those two questions now have been
answered. The next question is from
Valencia
and she asks, "Is this Jesus speaking
about Israel?" And she gives Zechariah
6-8.
>> Why don't we go there, brother James? Is
that
Zechariah 13?
>> Okay. Zechariah 13 6-8 says, "And one
shall say unto him, what are these
wounds in thy hands?" Then he shall
answer, "Those which were those with
which I was wounded in the house of my
friends. Awake, oh sword, against my
shepherd, and against the man that is my
fellow, sayeth the Lord, of host. Smite
the shepherd, and the sheep shall be
scattered. And I will turn my hand upon
the little ones. And it shall come to
pass that in all the land, sayeth the
Lord, two parts that end shall be cut
off and die, but the third shall be left
therein.
>> All right. Question one more time on
that, Deborah.
Uh
is Jesus speaking about Israel
with that's those scriptures. Zechariah
13 6-8
>> open to the pan
>> verse 6 that's that's talking about a
lot of false prophets and stuff man
>> right
>> preachers
>> and right and when they don't for an
example when they don't get raptured
like they've been telling the people
they going the people going to be
looking for they preachers that been
lying to them and they going to wound
them and then they going to ask him
where where you get them wounds from he
going to come up with this story. I was
wounded in the house of my friends.
>> All right. But from seven on down, that
was talking about the Lord, you know, uh
uh when he said, "Awake, oh sword,
against my shepherd, against the man
that is my fellow." That's the u lord
and the father. The lord being the
fellows with the uh father and they
going to smite the lord who is the
shepherd. And uh remember when the
disciples fled,
>> it was prophesied they was do that.
Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Anybody else want to add something?
>> Let's correct what you said about that
verse six dealing with those preachers
because read that verse five, James. We
didn't start there, but read verse five.
>> Verse four.
>> Or four. Let's pick it up at four.
>> Verse four says, "And it shall come to
pass in that day that the prophet shall
be ashamed every one of his vision. when
he hath prophesied, neither shall they
wear a rough garment to deceive.
But he shall say, "I am no prophet. I am
an husbandman. For men taught me to keep
cattle from my youth."
[Music]
>> So yeah, that that's uh like Jerome was
saying too, that's dealing with those
false prophets who go say, "I was no
preacher. I was a farmer." Mhm.
>> Somebody's own parents going to do
something to him.
>> Yep.
>> Pierce them through. Right.
>> Yeah. We can pick it up. You want to
pick it up there? Verse three. And it
shall come to pass when any man shall
>> verse three
>> verse verse three says and it shall come
to pass that when any shall yet prophesy
then his father and his mother that
begott him shall say unto him thou shalt
not live for thou sh
>> verse one okay verse one says in that
day there shall be a fountain open to
the house of David and to the
inhabitants of Jerusalem for sin and for
uncleanness.
And it shall come to pass in that day,
saith the Lord of hosts, that I will cut
off the names of the idols out of the
land, and they shall be no more
remembered. And also I will cause the
prophets and the unclean spirit to pass
out of the land.
And it shall come to pass that when any
shall yet prophesy, then his father and
his mother that begott him shall say
unto him, "Thou shalt not live, for thou
speaketh lies in the name of the Lord,
>> and his father and Mhm."
>> That's the whole thing in a nutshell. is
talking about follow these false prophet
that's going to be lying their own
parents going to kill them
and then those that escape what's going
to happen keep reading
and his father and his mother that
begott him shall thrust him through when
he prophesieth
and it shall come to pass in that day
that the prophet shall be ashamed every
one of his vision when he hath
prophesied neither shall there wear a
rough garment to deceive seeds,
but he shall say, "I am no prophet. I am
in husband men, for men taught me to
keep cattle from my youth."
>> And that's cuz he escaped when they was
trying to kill him. And after that, the
rest of it talking about Jesus.
>> Yep. Yep. And and even in that verse
seven where it say, "And they shall
smite the shepherd and the sheep shall
be scattered." Go to the Mark 14 right
quick. Uh well, James and just read that
verse. Pick it up at that verse 27.
>> Okay. Mark 14.
>> Yep. It's Jesus saying it out his own
mouth in the New Testament. Mark 14 and
27.
>> It says, "And Jesus saith unto them, all
ye shall be offended because of me this
night. For it is written, I will smite
the shepherd, and the sheep shall be
scattered."
>> but after that I am risen. I will go
before you into Galilee.
>> Yep. So yeah, that's Jesus too in that
verse seven
shepherd. So uh sister Deborah, we got a
time check.
>> Uh yes. Uh there's one question that you
all can answer very quickly
uh about the feast days and her on her
training day. So I want to read this
question to you all. Uh Eia
McCall
uh says there are a total of three of
the Lord's feast days that falls on my
training days.
During training, we can't miss more than
16 hours. Can you please guide me with
scriptures?
>> Right. Open to the panel.
Oxfell in the whale.
>> Yep.
>> Yep. Sometimes you just
>> Sometimes you just can't can't escape
your ox falling in the whale.
Uh, can we go and read that?
>> Somebody looking it up.
>> Yeah, we're in search mode.
Uh, Luke 14. Let's try that. Luke 14.
Let's see what we come up with that.
Luke 14.
And um
let's pick it up at that verse three. Uh
two pick up verse two.
>> One one James last question. One
>> verse chapter Luke 14 and verse one.
>> Yes.
>> And it came to pass as he went into the
house of one of the chief Pharisees to
eat bread on the Sabbath day, they
watched him. And behold, there was a
certain man before him, which had the
dropsy. And Jesus answering spake unto
the lawyers and Pharisees, saying, Is it
lawful to heal on the Sabbath day?
And they held their peace. And he took
him and healed him and let him go and
answered them, saying, "Which of you
shall have an ass or an ox fallth into a
pit, and will not straightway pull him
out on the Sabbath day?"
And they could not answer him again to
these things. And he put forth a parable
to those which were bidden when he
marked how they chose out the chief
rooms, saying unto them, when thou art
>> Uhhuh.
>> Yeah.
>> What it's telling you is some things
happen like your uncle your ass fall
into the into the uh pit well on the
Sabbath day. If you let him stay in
there, he going to die. So you have to
get him out. So sometime there are
things that uh uh uh that come up that
you just have to do in this man's world,
but you ain't going to do it all your
life. But that's equivalent to your ox
ass fall in the wheel in the pit. Just
have to deal with it. Something you
don't want to do, it's not your
pleasure. But the whole thing is this
what you might have to do so you can
feed yourself.
So the whole thing. So what I'm saying
is is like like Jesus said, some things
sometime things come up on the Sabbath
days or on the high days that you can't
have you can't get away that uh uh you
can't get away from. You have to deal
with it. That's all I have to say.
>> All right.
So
sister Deborah, time check. Yes, the
time is uh 9:05. And brother Cornell, uh
would you like to uh tell the audience
what will be going on for tomorrow?
>> Oh, yeah. So, uh like we opened up and
we said, uh happy atonement to everybody
all around the world that have tuned in
with us. And tomorrow we're going to
have our atonement lesson begins at 12
noon. And after our atonement lesson, 30
minutes after that, we're going to have
a Q&A, question and answer. 30 minutes
after a regularly scheduled atonement
lesson. So,
>> it will start Yeah, it will start at 300
p.m.
>> I have something to add to that, too.
>> Yes, sir.
>> I won't be a part of it.
[Laughter]
>> Oh.
All right.
>> Only thing I want to say that you have
people that have medical conditions and
people you know that severe diabetics.
Uh if you have medical condition and you
have to take your medicine, it could be
dire consequences. Or if you're a
diabetic and you have to eat or drink
something uh uh uh uh because it could
cause you have a uh uh go into a
diabetic seizure, then you should take
that into consideration.
If you have a condition that fasting
could cause longtime sickness or death,
then uh uh you have to pray to the Lord
because he understand and you go ahead
on and deal with what you have to deal
with because uh uh uh because of your
condition.
>> Yes, sir.
>> Yeah. So if you have to drink some water
because of sick
>> or take a medicine because of sickness,
then I suggest you do so.
>> That's all I have to say.
>> Yeah. All right. So, we'd like to thank
everybody from all around the world who
tuned in with us this evening, and we
hope that you continue to stay prayed up
and be safe. And may the Lord have mercy
on us all as brother James closes us
out. And once again, happy atonement to
you all.
Our Father, which art in heaven,
hallowed be thy name. Thy kingdom come,
thy will be done in earth as it is in
heaven. Give us this day our daily
bread. And forgive us our debts as we
forgive our debtors. and lead us not
into temptation, but deliver us from
evil. For thine is the kingdom and the
power and the glory forever. In Jesus
name we pray. Amen.
>> Amen.